Stephen Ward

Full-Stack Web Developer

Las Vegas, NV srmward@gmail.com

702.885.2832

Experienced web developer with a passion for employing modular, isomorphic design strategies to complex systems. Self-taught software development experience with comfort in both open-source and enterprise platforms. The goal is to build something that changes the world in a positive way.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Web Developer

Scalable Group - Las Vegas, NV February 2016 to Present

Build, configure, and maintain several LAMP/LEMP stacks in different environments

Configure and maintain RESTful APIs using the Laravel framework, Node.js

Migrate legacy projects into responsive, performant applications

Maintain report automation app and other microservices built with Node.js. Express.js

Enhance user experience and ad layout based on device and referrer

Implement and maintain Redis cache layers on various projects

Create full-scale web applications using the Laravel framework

Implement full-stack changes to hosted sites (HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES2015) and PHP)

Participate and assist with agile development team strategies

Freelance Web Developer

Self-employed - Las Vegas, NV May 2015 to Present

Build API servers using Node and Express

Manage Heroku dynos

Develop full-stack applications using React, Redux, and other performant JavaScript libraries

Handle all build and site-hosting logistics for a group of small businesses in the Las Vegas, Nevada area.

IT Analyst

Wynn Las Vegas - Las Vegas, NV September 2014 to February 2016

Responsibilities

Push development builds to our various staging and production environments, develop front-end code for the WynnLasVegas.com website as well as the company's HR portal, troubleshoot issues across environments related to IIS and DFS management, draft and present change documentation to IT leadership for approval, maintain all PeopleSoft access and application functionality.

Accomplishments

Successfully deployed PeopleSoft upgrades, WynnLasVegas.com site redesign and installation of Sitecore as its content management system, made several modifications to the web booking engine widget on the company website using jQuery to improve performance

Skills Used

Ability to code HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C# within the .NET framework, comfortable with MVC framework, ability to troubleshoot web and network issues

IT Desktop Support

Wynn Las Vegas - Las Vegas, NV November 2013 to August 2014

Responsibilities

As a desktop support technician, I was the first line of defense for all hardware- and software-related issues. Job duties included creating and deploying images for PCs, troubleshooting at all stages of the OSI model, and setting up for events across the two properties

Accomplishments

The position allowed me to put into action the work I was performing in college, allowed for hands-on experience to assist in all layers of the OSI model

Skills Used

More than anything, the position instilled in me the ability and tenacity to solve any technology-related problem placed in front of me.

Contract Stringer

Reuters

September 2011 to April 2014

Contract Stringer September 2011 - Present

n• Reported breaking national news under a strict deadline, including the Reno Air Races plane crash and the death of a Hells Angels motorcycle club chapter president.

n• Learned about the organization's editing process and ghostwriting techniques.

Lab Technician

Portland State University - Portland, OR January 2013 to September 2013

Responsibilities

Assist in teaching students about the C++, Java, and Python programming languages, tutor students when needed about discrete mathematics and algorithm design.

Skills Used

Ability to review and debug code written in various programming languages, networking with students and communicating effectively in order to teach them the foundations of computer science through experimentation

Managing Editor

The Nevada Sagebrush June 2011 to May 2012

Managed the development and deployment processes for the WordPress CMS.

Oversaw 12 writers and the weekly production of the student paper.

Wrote long-form stories investigating student finances and loans while editing design, articles and online content. Maintained the organization's social media accounts and redesign initiatives with a focus on engaging readers.

Education

Computer Science

Portland State University - Portland, OR 2012 to 2013

Bachelor's in Journalism and English Literature

University of Nevada - Reno, NV 2007 to 2012

Skills

.NET (2 years), PHP (3 years), MVC (2 years), HTML (5 years), Javascript (4 years), CSS3 (5 years), Sitecore (2 years), JQuery (4 years), Node.js (3 years), Angular.js (1 year), SQL (2 years), C# (2 years), Git (4 years), C++ (4 years), Wordpress (5 years), ReactJs (1 year), Redux (1 year), Express (2 years), RESTful API (2 years)

Links

https://github.com/srmward

Awards

2012 News Student of the Year

June 2012

Personally selected by the dean as the top-performing student in my class of 300+ students